{"test_questions": [[{"question": "In case of incomplete dominance, the phenotypic ratio of a monohybrid cross will be", "opta": "1:2:1", "optb": "3:1:1", "optc": "1:3:1", "optd": "1:1:2", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the meiotic cell divison in daughter cells are produced by two successive division in which", "opta": "first division is equational, second is reductional", "optb": "first division is reductional and second is equational", "optc": "both divisions are reductional", "optd": "both divisions are equational", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the approximate size (in kb) of the melon mitochondrial genome?", "opta": "600 kilobase", "optb": "1200 kilobase", "optc": "2400 kilobase", "optd": "3000 kilobase", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When an organism has a life cycle with alternation of generations, the haploid generation is the", "opta": "zygote", "optb": "gametophyte", "optc": "gamete", "optd": "sporophyte", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When do kinetochore microtubules pull chromosomes towards opposite spindle poles?", "opta": "In anaphase A", "optb": "In anaphase B", "optc": "In metaphase", "optd": "In telophase", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "During meiosis crossing over takes place at", "opta": "zygotene stage", "optb": "diplotene stage", "optc": "diakinesis stage", "optd": "pachytene stage", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following transposable elements are not found in plants?", "opta": "Ac", "optb": "Tam3", "optc": "L1", "optd": "All are found", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A plasmid used to introduce BT toxin into a plant cell", "opta": "carries an antibiotic resistance gene that makes the plant resistant to antibiotics", "optb": "causes the plant to produce opines", "optc": "is toxic for the plant cell", "optd": "carries a bacterial gene with a plant promoter", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The homologous chromosomes follow the process of synopsis in the", "opta": "leptotene", "optb": "zygotene", "optc": "pachytene", "optd": "diplotene", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When F1 plants are crossed with homozygous recessive plants, it is known as", "opta": "test cross", "optb": "recessive cross", "optc": "criss-cross", "optd": "para-cross", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The shortest of mitotic phases is the", "opta": "telophase", "optb": "interphase", "optc": "metaphase", "optd": "anaphase", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}